Guide to the Alpha Delta Phi Records, 1832 - 2017
Alpha Delta Phi Records 1832 - 2017
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Alpha Delta Phi
2016ADP
88.5 linear feet
212
The Alpha Delta Phi Records consist of materials related to the Middletown Chapter at Wesleyan University including its alumni groups, the Adelphic Educational Fund (AEF) and the Adelphic Literary Society (ALS). Ranging from 1832 - 2017, the materials include correspondence, minutes, annual reports, constitutions, by-laws, handbooks, manuals, invitations, newspaper and article clippings, photographs, postcards, publications, songbooks, histories, shirts, event posters, architectural drawings, banners, audio recordings, video recordings, and realia. The records cover the history of the chapter through its formation, development and management of the ALS and AEF, management of its eating club The Star & Crescent, its involvement with co-education, the split with the Alpha Delta Phi International Fraternity, the formation of the Alpha Delta Phi Society, and its relations with Wesleyan University.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Materials are closed for 75 years from the date of creation.
Acquisitions Information
On deposit to the Special Collections & Archives from The Adelphic Literary Society of Wesleyan University, of Middletown, Connecticut, and The Adelphic Educational Fund, Incorporated. Materials were acquired from 2016-2017.
Historical Note
The Middletown Chapter of the Alpha Delta Phi has served as a literary society to Wesleyan University students since its founding on July 31, 1856. At the 1856 Alpha Delta Phi convention in New Haven, Connecticut, two Wesleyan debating societies known as the Betrian Society and the Lebanian Society petitioned the International organization of Alpha Delta Phi for inclusion in the nationwide fraternity. It was decided to merge the two societies and a charter was granted to form the Middletown Chapter as the 18th chapter of the International. The two societies already had common ground with dining at the Chronometer Club and so merging the two worked with ease.
The new chapter moved quickly to renting halls in downtown Middletown for its meetings. In 1884, after the establishment and success of the Building Fund, the chapter erected its first house located on the former Neale property on the corner of High and Cross Streets. In this house, the chapter rented out rooms, held meetings and other events, and dined in its eating club The Star & Crescent Club for almost 20 years until numerous costly repairs necessitated the chapter to tear down the structure. Immediately, plans were drawn up for a larger house located on the same property. The second Middletown Chapter house was completed in 1905 and still houses ADP members and hosts meetings, reunions, weddings, and other Wesleyan or ADP related events.
In 1881 a group of Alpha Delta Phi alumni founded the Adelphic Literary Society (ALS) to support the intellectual and moral improvement of its members by developing ties among the undergraduate and post graduate members of the chapter. With the incorporation of the ALS chartered by the Legislature of the State of Connecticut, the ALS could legally own, maintain and transfer property for the Middletown Chapter, which it successfully did to allow the building of the chapter houses for undergraduate members. The ALS is also responsible for the chapter's eating club, the Star & Crescent, and it connects with its undergraduate members through alumni events on and off campus and serving as mentors.
As a way to sponsor intellectual growth of chapter members through public and educational activities at Wesleyan University, the Adelphic Educational Fund, Inc. (AEF) was established on December 14, 1944, and has since continued the support of intellectual and social life at Wesleyan. The tax-exempt AEF was founded by alumni led by George W. Davison, 1892, and Albert W. Johnston, 1893, to aid deserving undergraduates in the attainment of a college education at Wesleyan, with a preference for members of the Middletown Chapter of the Alpha Delta Phi. In addition to educational funding made available to students through the grant-in-aid program, the AEF also funds the Middletown Chapter's literary publication AdLit, literary events such as the Assembly Series, a Faculty Fellows program, and a community service program. It also funded educational programs which are now defunct, such as the Film Series and a Science Series.
Since its formation in 1856, the Middletown Chapter dealt with local and national issues. Undergraduate members lived years through wars, financial depressions, political unrest and fraternity tensions. During these times, the members came together to support one another and strived to come out on top. In the 1960s and 1970s when co-education was making waves across American universities and colleges, the Middletown Chapter began welcoming women members from Wesleyan's re-imagined co-ed student body, resulting in what is known among ADP members and alumni as the Co-Education Issue. While the International held firm against any of its chapters going co-ed, the undergraduate members of the Middletown Chapter endorsed the inclusion of women members. From 1972 until 1992, there was a constant debate to acknowledge women into the International, a struggle that ended in a split. On August 7, 1992 at the 160th Alpha Delta Phi Convention in Brainerd, Minnesota, a contract was approved by a 41-0 vote acknowledging the withdrawal of four chapters that wished to become co-educational chapters. These four co-educational chapters, Brunonian, Columbia, Middletown and Stanford, made up the newly formed Alpha Delta Phi Society. Other chapters would later leave the national fraternity and join the Society.
In 2006, the Middletown Chapter celebrated its sesquicentennial where they hosted a reunion, conducted oral history interviews, and published a history on the chapter's meeting and living areas titled Halls, Houses & Eating Clubs.
Collection Overview
The Alpha Delta Phi Records contain materials created or collected by members of the Middletown Chapter, the Adelphic Literary Society and the Adelphic Educational Fund and span from 1832-2017. Items found in the collection include correspondence, minutes, annual reports, constitutions, by-laws, handbooks, manuals, invitations, newspaper and article clippings, photographs, postcards, publications, songbooks, histories, shirts, event posters, architectural drawings, banners, audio recordings, video recordings, and realia. Audio and visual recordings found in the collection are in the format of reel to reel tape, audiocassette tapes, CD-Roms, videotapes and DVDs. The media format for these items is noted at the folder level. The records are housed in 154 archival document boxes, and 62 custom or oversize boxes.
Of note are the records of or created by Robert G. McKelvey, 1959. Through his years of service to the Middletown Chapter along with his roles of ALS President, AEF President, International President and Society President, Robert McKelvey's records cover many issues that faced the undergraduate and alumni body from the early 1970s to the present. Such issues included the rebuilding of the ALS, establishing a distinct division between the ALS and AEF, reducing debt, developing fundraising among the alumni, navigating the chapter and the International through the co-educational issue, and assisting with the formation of the Alpha Delta Phi Society. Also of note are the records of or created by William K. Wasch, 1952. Through his years of service to the Middletown Chapter along with his roles of Secretary/Treasurer for both the ALS and AEF, his files cover a significant portion of the organizations' histories along with a variety of issues that faced the Middletown Chapter including the transformation of the Society as it broke away from the Fraternity, the monumental debt reduction campaigns of the early 1990s and the financial struggles of the Star & Crescent Club throughout that decade.
Collection Arrangement
The records are arranged into 14 series which are found alphabetical by series name. Most of the 14 series have further been arranged in sub-series which are arranged alphabetically. Due to the variety of filing schemes practiced by the numerous contributors to this collection, files and papers are found in both chronological and reverse chronological order.
Series I: Adelphic Educational Fund (AEF), 1944-2016
Series II: Adelphic Literary Society (ALS), 1881-2015
Series III: Chapter - Alpha Delta Phi - Middletown Chapter, 1856 -, 1856-2017
Series IV: Co-Educational Issue, 1973-1991
Series V: House and Property, 1856-2011
Series VI: International, 1836-1992
Series VII: Ledgers, 1899-1992
Series VIII: Members, 1852-2015
Series IX: Memorabilia, 1959-2003
Series X: Photographs
Series XI: Society, 1992-2014
Series XII: Songbooks, 1859-2012
Series XIII: Wesleyan, 1946-2014
Series XIV: Publications, 1832-2008
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Alpha Delta Phi. Middletown Chapter (Wesleyan University).; Alpha Delta Phi. Songs and Music.; Architectural Drawings (visual works).; Coeducation. United States. History. 20th Century.; DVDs.; Flags.; Greek letter societies.; Oral histories (document genres).; Photographs.; Realia.; Scrapbooks.; Songbooks.; Sound Recordings.; Shirts (main garments).; T-shirts.; Tape reels.; Videotapes.; Adelphic Educational Fund (Middletown, Conn.).; Adelphic Literary Society (Middletown, Conn.).; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Alumni and alumnae.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Buildings.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Greek letter societies.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.).; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Students. History.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Series I: Adelphic Educational Fund (AEF) 1944-2016
  This series consists of the records created by members of the Adelphic Educational Fund, Inc., including the founding of the AEF, meeting minutes, by-laws, grant-in-aid applications, events sponsored by the AEF, financial documents and newspaper clippings. Materials for this series are housed in 12 document boxes, 5 linear feet.
  See also: Series II: ALS - Swain (Joseph R. Swain ALS Secretary-Treasurer 1948-1983)
  Series III: Chapter - Assembly Series
  Series VIII: Members - Personal Papers - Flannigan, E. Jenny K.
  Series VIII: Members - Personal Papers - McKelvey, Robert G.
  - AdLit, 1959-1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Articles of Association (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Assembly Series
    - 1958-2005 (Box 1, Folder 3-7)
    - Clippings, 1960s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - List of Events, 1955-2005 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Board Members, 1971-2005 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Board Room (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - By-Laws (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Butterfield Luncheon, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Finances
    - McKelvey 'history', 1966-2007 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bank Statements, 1948-1977 (Box 1, Folder 15-17)
  - Finances
    - Bank Statements, 1978-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence
      - McKelvey, 1968-2005 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
      - Swain, 1962-1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Tax Returns, 1973-1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Financial Aid
    This sub-series over time was also referred to as Grants, Grant-in-Aid, Adelphic Aid, or Scholarship.
    - 1950-1959 (Box 2, Folder 7-9)
    - [1996-2012] (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Applications, 1955-1964 (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1969 (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
    - Applications, 1965-1969 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1970-1975 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
    - Applications, 1970-1974 (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
    - Other Grants (past), 1970-1975 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Scholarship Chairman File, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
    - Scholarship Apps, Master File, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Scholarship Apps, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Grants, 1975-1986 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Applications, 1974-1983 (Box 5, Folder 4-11)
    - Applications, 1984-1992 (Box 6, Folder 1-8)
    - Applications, 1992-2000 (Box 7, Folder 1-8)
    - Applications, 2000-2008 (Box 8, Folder 1-8)
    - Applications, 2008-2015 (Box 9, Folder 1-7)
    - Recipients of the Adelphic Educational Fund Scholarship list (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Furniture Grant to ALS, 2003-2008 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Greene Night (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - History (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Meetings
    ALS & AEF meetings were often held jointly.
    - 2009-2016 (Box 10, Folder 1-8)
    - 1980-2008 (Box 11, Folder 1-10)
    - 1944-1979 (Box 12, Folder 1-9)
  - Tax Status, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Wesleyan, Gifts to (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Series II: Adelphic Literary Society (ALS) 1881-2015
  This series consists of the records created by members of the Adelphic Literary Society including financial records, meeting minutes, correspondence, fundraising records, alumni directories, annual reports, and by-laws. Materials for this series are housed in 31 document boxes, 13 linear feet.
  See also: Series VIII: Memebers - Personal Papers - Arnold, Herbert A.
  Series VIII: Members - Personal Papers - Cooper, Johnson G.
  Series VIII: Members - Personal Papers - Flanningan, E. Jenny K.
  Series VIII: Members - Personal Papers - Spencer, Donald
  Series VIII: Members - Personal Papers - Steffenson, James L.
  Series VIII: Members - Personal Papers - Wasch, William K.
  Series VIII: Members - Personal Papers - Yaus, Jeffrey
  - Alumni Directories
    - 1900-1940s (Box 12, Folder 12-15)
    - 1950s-1981 (Box 13, Folder 1-6)
  - Alumni Directory Misc., 1978 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Annual Report
    - 2010-2014 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - 1974-2009 (Box 14, Folder 1-8)
  - Archivist's Files
    - untitled, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Brown Alpha Delta Phi Archives (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - AEF Board Room Project, 2001-2007 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Future of Alpha Delt Archives (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Parchment Fraternal Greeting, Alpha Delta Phi (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Plaques (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Halls & Houses sources (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Halls & Houses, Comments & revisions (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - AEF History, docs from McKelvey (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Digital Photos (Box 15, Folder 3)
      Contains CDs - Moved to Series X: Photographs.
    - Info ADP (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Board Meetings
    All Meetings including committees.
    - 2012 September-2015 (Box 15, Folder 5-12)
    - 2012 February-May (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Virtual Board Meeting, 2011 December 19 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - 2011 February-November (Box 16, Folder 3-5)
    - & Homecoming, 2010 Fall (Box 16, Folder 6-7)
    - 2007 September-2010 May (Box 16, Folder 8-11)
    - 2001 September 15-2007 May (Box 17, Folder 1-22)
    - 1987-2001 May 24 (Box 18, Folder 1-35)
    - 1966-1986 (Box 19, Folder 1-16)
    - 1945-1965 (Box 20, Folder 1-6)
    - Index to ALS minutes, 1881-1906; and Minutes 1908 June 23-1952 June 6 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Board Members (Box 20, Folder 8)
    See also Series II: ALS - Board Meetings
  - By-Laws
    - 2006 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Draft, 2005 May (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Draft, 1993 November 4 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - 1934 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - 1895 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Chapter Relations
    - 1980-2002 (Box 20, Folder 14-16)
    - 1966-1979 (Box 21, Folder 1-15)
    - 1945-1965 (Box 22, Folder 1-9)
  - Financials
    - Bank Statements
      - Webster Bank, 2011; National Financial Services, 2008 April-2011 (Box 22, Folder 10-11)
      - Webster Bank, 2005 November-2008 March (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - Citizens Bank, 2005 November-2009 January (Box 22, Folder 13)
      - National Financial Services, 2006-2008 March (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - Webster Bank, 2009-2010 (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - Webster Bank, 1997 October-2008 (Box 23, Folder 1-10)
      - National Financial Services, 1999-2004 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Global Payments, 2002, 2013 (Box 23, Folder 12)
      - Hartford National Bank & Trust, 1954-1972 (Box 23, Folder 13-16)
    - Checkbooks, 1997-2009 (Box 24, Folder 1-5)
    - Checkbooks, 1968-1972 (Box 24, Folder 6-7)
    - Checkbooks, 1947-1962 (Box 25, Folder 1-5)
    - Account Books, 1958 December-1962 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Account Books, 1972-1998 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Account Books, 1972-2007 (Box 26)
    - Invoices, 1981-2008 (Box 27, Folder 1-12)
    - Chapter, 2011-2013 (Box 27, Folder 13-14)
    - Chapter, 1994-2011 (Box 28, Folder 1-16)
    - Star & Crescent, 2005-2013 (Box 28, Folder 17-21)
    - Star & Crescent, 2005-2013 (Box 29, Folder 1-4)
    - Star & Crescent, Bank Reports2007-2011 (Box 29, Folder 5-8)
    - Tax Documents, 2003-2012 (Box 29, Folder 9-18)
    - Tax Documents, 1937-1948, 1997-2002 (Box 30, Folder 1-7)
  - Flags (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Fundraising
    - 1992-2013 (Box 30, Folder 9-25)
    - A Decisive Moment & An Historic Opportunity, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 26)
    - Delegations, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 27)
    - Annual Giving, [1989] (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - 1985-1987 (Box 31, Folder 2-8)
    - Contributions, 1985 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - 1982-1984 (Box 31, Folder 10-12)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 32, Folder 1-2)
    - Contributors, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Contributions (Swain), 1979-1980 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - 1979 (Box 32, Folder 5-6)
    - Contributions, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - 1978 (Box 32, Folder 8-9)
    - Telethon, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Contributions, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Contributions, 1978 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - 1977 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Contributions (Swain), 1977 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Class Agent Materials, 1977-1980 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - 1976 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Contributions (Swain), 1975-1976 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Memorial Gifts, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - 1975 April-December (Box 33, Folder 8-9)
    - 1974-1975 March (Box 34, Folder 1-6)
    - Contributions, 1974 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Class Agents, 1974 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - (Swain), 1974-1981 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Contributions (Swain), 1974-1975 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - 1973 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - 1946-1972 (Box 35, Folder 1-20)
    - Letters, Samples, 1946-1981 (Box 35, Folder 21-26)
    - Letters-Miami, Samples (used as a model by A.L.S.), 1946-1981 (Box 35, Folder 27)
  - General, 1975-1978 (Box 35, Folder 28-29)
  - General, 1930-1974 (Box 36, Folder 1-11)
  - History (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Homecoming, 2010 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    See also Series III: Chapter - Time Capsule
  - House Finances
    - 1978-1981 (Box 36, Folder 14-16)
    - 1946-1977 (Box 37, Folder 1-7)
    - Bad Debt, 1968-1981 (Box 37, Folder 8-16)
    - Budget, 1971-1985 (Box 37, Folder 17-20)
  - House Insurance
    - 2005-2006 (Box 37, Folder 21-22)
    - 1946-2004 (Box 38, Folder 1-13)
    - Boiler, 1965-1968 (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Rice, Davis and Daley, 1948-1964 (Box 38, Folder 15-17)
  - House Lease, 1976-2008 (Box 39, Folder 1-8)
  - House Piano (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Letters From Alumni (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Mailing List (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - McKelvey
    - Dinner (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence
      - Board, 1972-1981 (Box 39, Folder 13)
      - Misc., 1974-1987 (Box 39, Folder 14-15)
    - Expenses, 1979-1981 (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - Finance
      - Acc, 1981-1983 (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Swain, Vasiliou, 1982-1983 (Box 40, Folder 2)
      - 1982 Mailing (Box 40, Folder 3-4)
      - Acc, 1982 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Membership Committee, 1975-1980 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Officers list (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Pete & Mike (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Sesquicentennial (Box 40, Folder 9-10)
  - Star & Crescent, 1965-1974 (Box 40, Folder 11-12)
  - Star & Crescent, 1942-1964 (Box 41, Folder 1-2)
  - State of the Chapter (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Swain
    Joseph R. Swain served as the ALS Secretary-Treasurer from 1948-1983.
    - 1970-1983 (Box 41, Folder 4-15)
    - 1950-1969 (Box 42, Folder 1-3)
    - (Riege), 1947-1949 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Alumni - Letters From, 1977-1983 (Box 42, Folder 5-6)
    - Ledger, [ca.1954-1960] (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Retirement Speech, 1983 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Tax Status (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Tax Exempt Status denied, Alfred T. Davison vs. IRS, 1932 (Box 42, Folder 10)
- Series III: Chapter - Alpha Delta Phi - Middletown Chapter, 1856 -, 1856-2017
  This series consists of records created by the undergraduate members of the Middletown Chapter of the Alpha Delta Phi. Also included are records related to the Star & Crescent, the chapter's eating club. Materials found within this series include the charter; constitution & by-laws; meeting minutes; correspondence; financial records; officer records, handbooks and manuals; invitations; time capsule and publications. Materials for this series are housed in 50 document boxes and two oversize boxes, 25.5 linear feet.
  See also Series VII: Ledgers
  - Alumni Reunion Invitations (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Assembly Series, 2001-2005 (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Assembly Series, 1980-1989 (Box 43, Folder 1-9)
    Contains VHS & tape reel.
  - Assembly Series, 1960-1980 (Box 44, Folder 1-5)
  - Chapter Minute Books list (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Chapter Minute Book, [1965? December]-[1972] October 6 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Chapter Minute Book, 1979 Spring-1985 Spring (Box 44, Folder 8-10)
  - Chapter Minute Book I, 1857 February-1872 April (Box 45)
  - Chapter Minute Book II, 1872 September-1877 April (Box 46)
  - Chapter Minute Book III, 1877 March-1886 June (Box 47)
  - Chapter Minute Book IV, 1886 September-1895 April (Box 48)
  - Chapter Minute Book V, 1895 April-1902 February 24 (Box 49)
  - Chapter Minute Book VI, 1902 February 28-1908 June (Box 50)
  - Chapter Minute Book VII, 1908 September-April 1916 10 (Box 51)
  - Chapter Minute Book VIII, 1916 April 18-1924 May (Box 52)
  - Chapter Minute Book, 1932 September-1934 March & 1936 March-1937 February (Box 53)
  - Chapter Minute Book, 1937 June-1942 September (Box 54)
  - Chapter Minute Book, 1942 September 20-1948 February 18 (Box 55)
  - Chapter Minute Book, 1948 February 18-1961 May 9 (Box 56)
  - Chapter Minute Book, 1985-1993 January (Box 57, Folder 1-4)
  - Chapter Minute Book, 1993 Spring-1995 Fall (Box 58, Folder 1-2)
  - Chapter Minute Book, 2000 May 7-2005 September (Box 58, Folder 3-5)
  - Chapter Minute Book, 1995 Fall-1998 September 16 (Box 59)
  - Chapter Minute Book, 1998 October 25-2000 April 30 (Box 60)
  - Chapter Minute Book, 2005 Fall-2008 February (Box 61, Folder 1-4)
  - Chapter Minute Book, 2008 Spring-2009 Spring (Box 62, Folder 1-2)
  - Chapter Minute Book Summaries (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Charter (original Middletown Chapter charter), 1856 July 31 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Checkbooks list (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Checkbooks, 1974-1980 (Box 62, Folder 6-10)
  - Checkbooks, 1945-1980 (Box 63, Folder 1-8)
  - Checkbooks, 1926-1939 (Box 64, Folder 1-6)
  - Checkbooks, 1921-1925 (Box 65)
  - Checkbooks, 1915-1916 (Box 66)
  - Checkbooks, 1914-1916 (Box 67)
  - Consensus Proposals, 2007-2011 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Constitution & By-Laws, etc.
    - By-Laws, pre-1909-2007 October 22 (Box 64, Folder 8-11)
  - Oversize, Composites (mini size), 1955-2014 (Box 189)
    Gaps in years
  - Constitution & By-Laws, etc.
    - By-Laws Committee Proceedings, 2007 (Box 68, Folder 1-3)
    - By-Laws Notebook (remnants), 1990 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Duties of Officers, ca.1944 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Constitution of the Alpha Delta Phi Middletown, adopted 1871 May 18 (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - History
    - untitled (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - History of Alpha Delta Phi by 1866 Historian of Middletown Chapter (incomplete) (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Piano Fund Drive, 1979 (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - Misc. - Middletown Chapter & other chapters (Box 68, Folder 10)